# VISHNU T

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

#### CONTACT

Cell No +91 9655495432

Email mrtvishnu@gmail.com

Website https://tvishnu.netlify.app/

Address

H.No. 3E-592/A, RK Towers,
Subash Chandra Bose Nagar,
New Hafeezpet,
(Near RTO Kondapur),
Gachi bowli - Miyapur road,
Hyderabad - 500049

#### **MY SKILLS**

Javascript

ReactJS

Redux

Express.js

MongoDB

Node.js

Python

MSSQL Server

HTML & CSS

#### **HOBBIES & INTEREST**







## Who am I?

I'm a JS developer & MERN Stack Enthusiast currently based in Hyderabad. I love everything that has to do with Coding & Problem solving, Automization, Application development. I have more than 4 years of experience working as a Software developer.

I love working with people, especially if they have the same passion.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Full Stack Developer 09/2020 - 12/2020
 Source IT Soulutions - Hyderabad, Telangana

Was working for Equinix, in their platform to manage their Data centres.
We were using MERN Stack Typescripted.

Full Stack Developer **04/2020 - 09/2020** 

Smarter Dharma - Bommasandra, Karnataka

Participating in full lifecycle of development for company's web application using MERN Stack from scratch.

Maintaining the API and also involved in testing and desinging.

Full Stack Developer 10/2019 - 03/2020

GeekSkool - Bangalore, Karnataka

Develop UIs with JavaScript, HTML and CSS Created RESTful APIs for increased scalability of the application Worked on multiple technologies like Postgres SQL, Redis, etc.,

Software Developer **01/2017 - 09/2019** 

ZeOmega - Bangalore, Karnataka

Wrote SQL queries to manage data from the database using MSSQL Server Worked on Sentinel rule based engine and backend.

Also, worked on React in the front-end part

#### **EDUCATION**

M.S., Software Engineering 2011 - 2016VIT University

It's an Integrated course of 5 years. Graduated with 7.93 CGPA

Higher Secondary Schooling **2009 - 2011**SRV Matriculation School

Took up Computer Science group. Passed out with 81.5 %



https://github.com/vishnu-t hivaqaraian



https://www.linkedin.com/i n/vishnu-thiyagarajan-2aa6 a6129/

#### **COMPANY PROJECTS**

#### **Tools**

MUI, React, Nodejs, Next, Mongoose, Mongo DB

MUI, React, VS code, Postman, Nodejs, Express, Mongoose, Mongo DB

BootStrap, React, Sublime text, Postman, Zope, Python, MSSQL

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

MUI, React, Redux, VS code, Postman, Firebase

React hooks, MUI VS code, Postman, Mongo DB

MUI, React, VS code, Nodejs, Express, Mongoose, Mongo DB

## **PROJECTS**

## **Equinix**

Equinix data center services support evolving technology requirements, design and deploy the right cage, suite and server cabinet solutions.

I was dedicated to build the functionalities for the platform in front-end and back-end for the client requirements.

#### **SD Plus CASA**

SD wants to push the boundaries of conventional building standards and norms to achieve a perfect synergy of design & technology.

My work was to design the front-end and data flow within the app and build it accordingly.

In the back-end, worked to achieve Rest API and developed a Calculus Engine for the algorithms.

## Sentinel Rule based engine

It's an intelligent automation that removes the human error factor, helping to ensure accuracy across tasks. No submitting tickets. No waiting. Just done fast and right. I worked in the development side of the engine where they can configure rules based on the events, criteria and actions.

#### **Insurance Assessment Module**

The Assessment activity module is a way for insurance providers to support client's assessments. Where, the upcoming questions are dynamically generated based on the previous answers.

#### Template engine

It allows users to easily generate PDF documents and reduce the effort and automates the process of creating and managing their document templates from the assessments they have answered with the needed education materials.

#### **Socialize**

It's a fun project in an attempt to clone Twitter, where people can post content and view, like, comment other's post.

### To-do app

This is a typical To-do application reflecting the same functionalities of Ubuntu To-do. Here, the tasks can be added, updated, deleted and managed with list of tasks.

### **Casa Foods**

It's a platform where users can customize their food by adding their core recipe. Which allows Nutritionists to customize diet based on their weight, age, etc.,